Now that we've gone through the common actions and phrases that we need to describe how to prepare a
现在我们已经了解了描述如何准备
particular food we can actually get into a real example before we do that.
在我们这样做之前，我们实际上可以进入一个真实的例子。
I want to just cover for simple words that I think you probably already know but I just want to make
我只想涵盖我认为您可能已经知道但我只想制作的简单单词
sure these are very very clear.
当然这些都非常非常清楚。
Before we get into the example these are recipe dish servings and ingredients.
在我们进入示例之前，这些是菜谱和配料。
OK so very quickly the recipe is basically how to make that particular food whatever it may be.
好的，很快，食谱基本上就是如何制作特定的食物，无论它是什么。
It includes the actions descriptions of the actions as well as how much of each particular thing that
它包括动作的动作描述以及每个特定事物的数量
you need.
你需要。
That's what a recipe is.
这就是食谱。
So how much I need and what I need to do with that amount of each thing.
所以我需要多少，我需要用每一件事的数量做些什么。
Pretty simple.
很简单。
That's usually the hard part.
这通常是最困难的部分。
It's basically like a computer program.
它基本上就像一个计算机程序。
Do this and then do this with this much and then do this with this much.
这样做，然后用这么多做这个，然后用这么多做这个。
OK.
好的。
So you just follow it step by step and it usually includes some of the phrases that we were just talking
所以你只需一步一步地跟着它，它通常包括我们刚刚谈论的一些短语
about after that's done.
大约在完成之后。
When you finish that or when it's golden brown ad then it will say an amount for example a tablespoon
当你完成它或者当它是金棕色的广告时，它会说一个数量，例如一汤匙
a teaspoon a cup and different countries have different ways to measure things that are needed.
一茶匙一杯，不同的国家有不同的方法来衡量需要的东西。
In America we often use cups we use tablespoons.
在美国，我们经常使用杯子，我们使用汤匙。
We don't usually use for example grams so much or or milligrams.
我们通常不使用例如克这么多或毫克。
We don't use that as often.
我们不经常使用它。
OK then we have ingredients ingredients are the things that we actually put in what we're making the
好的，那么我们有成分成分是我们实际放入的东西，我们正在制作
vegetables the meat the spices all of the things that we need all the stuff.
蔬菜 肉 香料 所有我们需要的东西 所有的东西。
Those are the ingredients.
这些是成分。
So the ingredients go into the recipe and once we do the recipe then we have finished preparing a particular
所以成分进入食谱，一旦我们完成食谱，我们就完成了一个特定的准备
dish.
盘子。
So dish can be a little confusing one meaning of dish is something like a plate or a a bowl but one
所以菜可能有点令人困惑菜的一个含义是像盘子或碗但是一个
meaning of dish is a particular type of food.
菜的意思是一种特殊的食物。
So we're going to talk about the dish.
所以我们要谈谈这道菜。
We're going to talk about is stir fried tomato and eggs.
我们要谈的是炒番茄和鸡蛋。
It's a classic Chinese dish.
这是一道经典的中国菜。
And maybe your country wherever you may be from has classic dishes things that everybody knows and maybe
也许你的国家无论你来自哪里都有经典的菜肴，每个人都知道，也许
everybody knows how to cook those dishes or maybe at least many people know how to cook those dishes.
每个人都知道怎么做这些菜，或者至少很多人知道怎么做这些菜。
Some people just cannot cook and that's OK too.
有些人就是不会做饭，这也没关系。
OK.
好的。
Now when you're preparing dishes using a recipe with ingredients you need to know how many people you're
现在，当您使用带有配料的食谱准备菜肴时，您需要知道您有多少人
going to have.
将会有。
And the reason that you need to know that is because you may need more or less ingredients OK.
你需要知道的原因是因为你可能需要更多或更少的成分。
So the way that we count how much we need to make is usually by using the word servings.
因此，我们计算需要制作多少的方法通常是使用“份”这个词。
We might say three servings of this if you make for example a box of brownies or cake on the box on
如果你在盒子上做一盒巧克力蛋糕或蛋糕，我们可能会说三份
the back it says four servings.
背面写着四份。
That generally means that it's enough for four people.
这通常意味着四个人就足够了。
Now the way that that's exactly calculated and measured is not so clear.
现在，精确计算和测量的方式还不是很清楚。
But generally speaking we're talking about how many people are going to eat.
但一般来说，我们谈论的是要吃多少人。
How many people need to eat that particular dish.
有多少人需要吃那道菜。
So how many servings do we need to make while 30 servings.
那么我们需要做多少份，而 30 份。
We need a lot of ingredients.
我们需要很多配料。
We're having a huge party tonight.
今晚我们有一个盛大的聚会。
30 servings of whatever you're making.
30 份你正在做的任何东西。
OK.
好的。
So I hope those four words are very clear because they're very important when it comes to describing
所以我希望这四个词非常清楚，因为它们在描述时非常重要
how to make a particular thing.
怎么做ke 一个特定的东西。
OK.
好的。
Now let's actually go into our recipe.
现在让我们真正进入我们的食谱。